mycronic.com 2019-07-26

# Privacy policy

#### Introduction

Privacy is recognized as a fundamental human right and Mycronic understand that privacy is important for visitors to the Mycronic Internet sites and related domains.

Mycronic wants all of its online visitors to be confident that we process information about you in accordance with applicable privacy legislation. This privacy policy (the “ **Privacy Policy** ”) is designed to help you understand what personal data (any information that may identify you as an individual person such as name, address, IP-number etc.) we collect on our websites and how we process such data in our capacity as a data controller. This Privacy Policy also describes your rights and how to proceed in case you wish to exercise them.

It is important to us that you feel safe in our processing of your personal data. Mycronic would never sell your personal data or release your data to another party in other ways than as follows from this Privacy Policy.

We welcome you to visit all digital channels managed by Mycronic and you do not need to provide any personal data to visit them. However, please be aware that if you do not provide some requested information, access to certain services or parts of our digital channels and certain social media channels may be restricted.

####   
Personal data processing

**What personal data does Mycronic process about you and for what purposes?**

Your "personal data" means information or pieces of information that allows us to identify you as an individual. This typically includes information such as your name, address, email address, and telephone number, but can also include other information such as IP address. 

We may use your personal information to:

  * handle job applications,
  * provide you with information about open job positions,
  * provide you with answers regarding our products or services that you request from us, 
  * improve our products and services,
  * provide you with requested invitations, newsletter and investor related information,
  * evaluate the use of our websites and your experience on our websites including collection of information about the device you are using to view our websites, such as your IP address or the type of Internet browser or operating system you are using, and link this to your personal information so as to ensure that the websites present the best web experience for you, for additional information about our use of cookies please see our cookie policy,
  * personalize your website experience, as well as to evaluate (anonymously and in the aggregate) statistics on website activity, such as what time you visited it, whether you’ve visited it before and what site referred you to it,
  * analyze the effectiveness of our marketing activities,
  * contact you regarding products and services which may be of interest to you, (provided we have an existing customer relationship with you or that you have given us your consent to do so).
  * provide a secure environment through surveillance at our premises.

For further information regarding personal data processing please follow this link.   

**Your rights**

You are entitled to request information regarding our processing of your personal data, if any. _Please note that Mycronic may request certain details about you in order to ensure that the information is provided to the correct person and handled in a secure way._

Should you have reason to believe that any personal data that Mycronic holds about you is inaccurate, please let us know and we will update the information.

You may request us to delete personal data we hold about you. For example, if the information is no longer necessary to fulfill the purpose they were collected for. _Please note that, when legally required, Mycronic could decline your request, for example if the data is needed for tax or bookkeeping purposes, or are necessary to defend legal claims._

You also have the right to request limitations of the processing of your personal data. _Please note that in such cases, Mycronic may need to investigate the situation further prior to reaching a decision._ (You always have a right to opt out from direct marketing activities and request limitation of processing based on legitimate interest – including potential profiling for direct marketing purposes).

When you provide Mycronic either with your consent, or the processing is based on fulfillment of an agreement with you, you have, during certain circumstances a right to have your data transferred to another data controller. This however requires that the transfer is technically possible and may be carried out automatically.

**Information about children**

The Mycronic website is not intended for, or targeted at, children under the age of 13 years old and Mycronic never knowingly or intentionally collect information about children under this age. If you believe that Mycronic has collected information about a child, please use our contact form to request deletion of the information.

**Sensitive personal data and personal identification numbers**

Sensitive personal data includes any information that reveals your race or ethnicity, political views, religious or philosophical beliefs, membership in a trade union, as well as personal data regarding your health or private life.

Mycronic generally does not process any sensitive data about you. In case you provide us with sensitive personal data we will only process such data if we receive your consent for this or if such processing is legally required.

Mycronic limits the use of personal identification numbers and only process personal identification numbers when needed to ensure your identification.

**Sources of information**

Mycronic only processes personal data provided by you. In certain cases, Mycronic may supplement this data with information from third parties for the purpose of evaluating and improving our digital channels and services or if needed for a certain job position (in such case this information will be provided in the specific job ad).

The information that Mycronic collect from such third parties is as follows:

  1. Address information from public registries to ensure Mycronic have your correct address;
  2. Information from social media for marketing or anti-fraud purposes.

#### Information to other parties

**Data processors**

Other than as provided in this Privacy Policy, Mycronic will not share personal data you provide with any third party. In cases where it is necessary for Mycronic to carry out our services, we may retain external suppliers (processors) for services in connection to our digital channels or the services. These suppliers may process personal data and sometimes require limited access to personal data collected via our digital channels or services. Mycronic uses the following types of suppliers:

  1. Marketing (social media, media agencies, advertising agencies) such as LinkedIn.
  2. IT (companies that handle necessary operations, technical support and maintenance of our IT solutions such as IBM)
  3. Events, statistics and surveys (companies that handle evaluations, statistics and surveys of our services) such as Netigate.
  4. Recruitment tools such as Reachmee.
  5. Investor Relation services such as Computershare and TeamEngine.

Mycronic strives to limit third-party access and only share information that is necessary to fulfill the purpose of the processing. Mycronic ensures that our suppliers can meet our high standards and provide sufficient safeguards and require them to protect your personal data in accordance with this Privacy Policy and refrain from using or disclosing your personal data for any purpose. 

**Transfers to third countries**

Mycronic endeavors to keep personal data within the European Economic Area (EEA) but may engage suppliers located outside of the EEA such as other companies within the Mycronic Group or companies that assist with our technical support and maintenance of our IT services.

Any such data will always be kept to a minimum relevant for the purpose. No matter where your personal data is transferred, Mycronic always take necessary measures to ensure that the security level and processing is in line with GDPR, for example by using the EU Commission's Standard Clauses.

**Security**

Mycronic takes all appropriate technical and organizational security measures which are necessary to safeguard personal data against unauthorized access, modification, or destruction. _However, providing personal data over digital channels always entails a risk since it is not possible to completely protect technical systems from unauthorized access._

Mycronic has additional measures in place to protect sensitive personal data and personal identification numbers. Sensitive information provided to us on our website and/or transmitted to other websites is protected through the use of encryption.

**Deletion of data**

Personal data will not be stored for longer than is necessary in light of the purposes of the processing and, in general, Mycronic will delete personal data in the manner which follows from applicable legislation and in accordance with our Retention Policy. Where information is known to be unreliable, irrelevant or excessive, it will be securely deleted or anonymized as soon as is reasonably possible.

**Third party web applications**

The Mycronic website includes social media features, such as a Facebook ‘Like’ button and also widgets, such as the ‘Share this’ button, or interactive mini-programs that run on our website. These features may collect your IP address, which pages you visit on our website, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by third parties or directly on our website. Our website may also provide hyperlinks to other websites which are provided by other group companies or companies which do not belong to the Mycronic group.

_Please note that this Privacy Policy does not apply to these features. Your interactions with these features are governed by their privacy policies and other routines of the companies providing them._

**Amendments to the privacy policy**

This Privacy Policy may be updated from time to time, which will be indicated on top of the document. We recommend that users of our websites re-visit this Privacy Policy on occasion to learn of new privacy practices or changes to this Privacy Policy. You should not supply Mycronic with any personal data if you do not accept changes which are made to this Privacy Policy.

**Contact information**

If you have any questions regarding our Privacy Policy, want to exercise any of your rights, or have any other question regarding our processing, please contact us:

Postal adress:   
Mycronic AB   
Box 3141   
183 03 Täby   
Sweden

Visiting address:   
Nytorpsvägen 9   
183 53 Täby   
Sweden

Contact Form

**Complaints**

In case data is not being processed in accordance with this Privacy Policy or with the General Data Protection Regulation (EU) 2016/679, you have the right to file a complaint with the Supervisory Authority (Datainspektionen) or any other European Supervisory Authority.
